AFEENI PHILLIPS

Enthusiastic and ambitious Computer Information Systems graduate with over 2 years of professional experience and over 4 years of freelance web development experience. Strong understanding of web development fundamentals including HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript. Fast learner, hard worker, and team player who is proficient in an array of technical skills. Aspiring to combine a broad background with strong technical skills to excel.

EDUCATION

Howard University, School of Business, Washington, D.C.

May 2019

B.B.A in Computer Information Systems

Cumulative GPA: 3.30

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATES

Scrum Alliance Certified ScrumMaster (CSM)

June 2021

SKILLS

SQL, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, XML, Sass, WordPress, Bootstrap, ReactJS, Angular, TypeScript, Redux, Cypress, Jenkins, Jira, Confluence, Git, Java, Android SDK, Spring MVC, Shell Scripting, Visio, Final Cut Pro, iMovie, Adobe Premiere, Agile Methodology, Scrum

WORK EXPERIENCE

Royal Bank of Canada Capital Markets, Jersey City, NJ Technology Analyst

Jun 2018 - Aug 2018/Aug 2019 - Present

Experience as a backend engineer, front-end engineer, and business analyst as a part of a technical rotational program. Learn and practice Scrum Master and Agile skills from an internal Senior Scrum Master mentorship program. Implement automation, continuous integration, and continuous deployment using technologies such as Docker, Git, Jira, and Jenkins.

- Created internal web applications, using ReactJS, to onboard all RESTful APIs within an organization of over 8,000 employees, host data-visualization services, and display information about team products.
- Automated end to end JavaScript regression testing, using Cypress, to ensure applications work as needed and to find any detrimental bugs.
- Analyze, document, and convey anti-money laundering standards, as a business analyst, for recording payment transactions using workflows and Excel.
- Increased transparency between stakeholders by creating and publishing documentation for a group of 5 data visualization web applications.
- Communicate and resolve any inter-team impediments that would prevent assignments from moving forward, as the Scrum Master of the intern team.

Microsoft Tech Fellowship, Washington, D.C.

Dec 2017 - May 2018

Digital Pioneers Academy Intern

Assisted the founder/principal with recruitment and strategic communications of a start-up computer science focused middle school. Conveyed the mission, purpose, and importance of the start-up to prospective parents and students.

Instructed code-based activities with potential students in order to teach beginner programming skills, such as basic algorithms.

LEADERSHIP & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Howard University Capstone Project, Washington, D.C | Student (Technical Consultant)

Jan 2019 - May 2019

Presented Microsoft employees a strategy and recommendation for the IRS to move to the cloud using Microsoft Azure IaaS. Researched Azure Government and its products to provide useful recommendation to the chosen government organization. Ensured recommendations pass all necessary government requirements, such as FedRAMP.

 Acted as a Team Lead by communicating tasks, timelines, priorities, and leading communications with our point of contact at Microsoft.

Google Tech Exchange Program, Mountainview, CA | Student

Aug 2018 - Dec 2018

Completed team-based projects, in classrooms led by Howard University Computer Science professors and Google engineers.

- Created 3 technical products from scratch using development and product management skills.
- Improved technical skills while studying computer science at Google's corporate headquarters in Mountainview, CA.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

America Needs You, Los Angeles, CA | Mentor Coach

Oct 2020 - Present